「移花接木」是一种利用深伪技术
Correction is a method of real-time image manipulation
前情提要
进行实时图像处理的方法
using the deployment of deepfake technology.
他们为了保护它不惜杀人
They kill people to protect it.
你是伊冯吧
It's Yvonne, isn't it?
要是有什么我能帮上忙的
If there's anything I can do.
你可以去抓凶手
You can get the bastard who did it.
感谢美国合作方的干预
Thanks to the intervention of our US partners,
先锋行动现在安全了
Operation Vanguard is secure.
我今早去了局长办公室
I stopped by the Commissioner's office this morning,
提交了我的7-28申请表
handed in my 728.
-你要辞职吗 -别担心 吉玛
- You're resigning? - Don't worry, Gemma.
我没说出辞职的真实原因
I didn't give the real reason.
艾萨克 之前的约定没变
Isaac, the deal is still intact.
什么约定
What deal?
有人来找过你了 是吧
Somebody got to you, didn't they?
有了这样的能力 你能做到你梦想的所有善事
And with power, you can do all the good you ever dreamt of.
我去找过艾萨克·特纳了 他不信任我们
I was with Isaac Turner. He doesn't trust us.
-这是你的错 -你小声点
- And that is your fault. - Lower your tone.
没有人能在镜头外对我嚷嚷
I don't let anyone raise their voice at me off camera.
我情况怎么样
What am I looking at?
四期胃癌
Stage 4 stomach cancer.
-喂 -我需要你帮我个忙
- Hello? - I need you to do something for me.
浴室里
Look in the bathroom.
有个笔记本
There's a laptop.
格雷戈里·诺克斯 你因妨碍公务被捕了
Gregory Knox, I am arresting you for obstructing a police officer.
你怎么说
What are you saying?
你加入吗
You in?
嗯
Yes.
发生交火 危险已解除
Shots fired. Threat neutralised.
目标倒下 重复 目标倒下
Target down. Repeat. Target down.
一切都井井有条
Everything's falling perfectly into place.
哈特指挥官和总警司加兰德也在场
Also present was Commander Hart and DSU Garland,
他们说政府通讯总部有多达50个行动人员
who stated there are up to 50 operatives across... GCHQ
同时出席的还有安全大臣 艾萨克·特纳
Also present... was the Security Minister, Isaac Turner.
我是总督察瑞秋·凯里
This is DCI Rachel Carey.
用隐藏摄像头录制
In place of hidden camera recording,
拍摄此视频是记录我作为目击证人的证词
I'm filming this eyewitness testimony for my dossier detailing
详细说明系统性的非法算改视频证据的行为
the systematic illegal practice of video evidence tampering
也就是所谓的「移花接木」
known as corrections.
我问问你
Let me ask you something.
你觉得人会变吗
You think a person can change?
我不知道我会不会变
I don't know if I do.
你告诉我们你会变的
You told us you could change.
我的英国朋友们信了
My British chums went for it.
丹尼·哈特是个用下体思考的家伙
Danny Hart, thinking with his famous hard-on.
加兰德
Garland.
只有上帝知道她在想什么
God only knows what she was thinking of.
我告诉过他们
Me, I told them...
眼见为实
..I'll believe it when I see it.
但是你 快道小姐
As for you, fast track.
你啊 你最好祈祷人是会变的
Boy, you better pray a person can change.
你能不能活着出去就靠这个了
The only hope you have of getting out of here alive depends on it.
真相捕捉
第二季  第六集
本季完
喂
Hello?
抱歉这个时候打扰你
Sorry for the unsociable hour.
帝国反击了
The empire's struck back.
■
"一派胡言"
罗文·吉尔回应吹哨人的指控
吉尔 内政大臣就是不肯罢休
Gill, the Home Sec that just won't die.
我们需要重新部署 作出回应
We need to regroup. Respond.
车在路上了
The car's on its way.
好
Erm...OK.
你听过录音了吧
I mean, you heard the recording, right?
他已经承认和爱丽莎合谋阻碍了维多利亚·贝洛的申请
I have got him admitting he colluded with Aliza to obstruct Victoria Bello's application.
向你致敬 艾萨克
And for that, I salute you, Isaac.
但是仅仅有这个还不算战术
But that alone is not a strategy.
是时候启动杀死吉尔行动了
It's time to launch Operation Kill Gill.
我会带点心来 你有对什么过敏吗
I'll bring pastries. Any allergies?
有什...
Any...?
没有
No. Erm...
格雷戈里 这样安全吗
..Gregory, is...is this safe?
我是说这样打电话
I mean, us talking on the phone like this.
只要是在和我打电话 艾萨克
So long as it's me you're talking to, Isaac,
你就是安全的
you're safe.
看镜头
Face the camera.
读出高亮的那一段
Read the highlighted paragraph.
官方声明
大点声
Aloud.
我 瑞秋·凯里 明白...
I...Rachel Carey... understand...
我去 我让你大声点
Oh, Colonel Kurtz. I said aloud.
我 瑞秋·凯里
I, Rachel Carey,
明白我正处于美利坚合众国的合法管辖范围内
understand that I am currently within the legal jurisdiction of the United States of America.
只要我还在
Whilst I remain within the legal jurisdiction
美国的管辖范围内
of the United States of America,
就受到美国联邦法律
I am bound by the rules, regulations
和法规的限制
and limitations of US federal law.
奇怪 你指望别人遵守你们的法律
Strange - expecting others to obey your laws
但是却一直触犯我们的法律
while you break every last one of ours.
安静点 小野猫
Settle down, wildcat.
你已经负伤了
You've already got one battle scar.
你为什么对这么重要的情报隐瞒不报呢
Why did you withhold this critical piece of intelligence?
摄像头拍到了俄罗斯派遣的刺客
Russian state assassin captured on camera.
-你却不说 -没有律师在场我是不会说的
- You didn't share it? - I'm not talking without a lawyer.
你没有被捕
You're not under arrest.
那就加兰德吧
Garland, then.
你说什么
Beg your pardon?
我要总警司吉玛·加兰德出席我的审讯
I want DSU Gemma Garland present at my interrogation.
我猜她正看着我呢
I'm guessing she's in on this, too.
对吧
Right?
抱歉 孩子
Sorry, kiddo.
妈妈不在家
Momma's not home.
你跟我仔细说说这图片是哪儿来的
Why don't you tell me exactly how you got a hold of this image.
我也想问你
I'd like to ask you the same thing.
我很想在问问题的间隙用湿布捂住你的脸
I'd like to put a soaking cloth over your face between questions.
但是我最近在练习克制
But...I'm exercising restraint.
格雷戈里·诺克斯分享给你的是吧
Gregory Knox shared this with you, didn't he?
我强烈推荐你自己也练练
I strongly suggest you exercise some yourself.
但是你已经知道口罩下的人是谁了
But you already knew who the man behind the mask was.
尼古拉·米尔斯基 如果这是他的真名的话
Nikolai Mirsky, if that's his name.
你记得我们谈过改变的事吧
Remember when we talked about change?
-他不是俄罗斯人 对吧 -从现在开始就再好不过了
- He's not a Russian national, is he? - Now would be a good time to start.
我会说他本来是为你工作的
I'm going to say he worked for you
直到他变成了累赘
until he became a liability,
你就让他的搭档打爆了他的头
and you had his partner blow his brains out.
我是想做对的事
I mean...I try to do the right thing.
我不知道你和格雷戈里·诺克斯在谋划什么
I don't know what you're plotting with Gregory Knox,
-但是我希望这是值得的 -为了什么呢
- but I do hope it's worth it. - And for what?
-好像中途死了很多人 -自视甚高的快道公主
- A lot of people seem to be dying in the process. - An entitled fast-track princess...
-爱迪生·姚 约瑟夫·姆旺吉 杰森·麦肯纳 -一堆废话在我的耳边
- Edison Yao. Joseph Mwangi. Jason McKenna. - ..yap-yap-yapping... in my ear
-李·布拉德伯里 -不知道什么时候该
- Lee Bradbury. - ..doesn't know when...
-帕特里克·弗林 -他妈的闭嘴
- Patrick Flynn. - ..to shut the fuck up!
那小子运气真的差
Your boy had shitty luck.
看到了不该看的东西
Saw something he shouldn't.
这种事时有发生
It happens.
但是你 从另一方面来讲
But you, on the other hand - nah,
你很幸运 不是吗
you got all the luck in the world, don't you?
带着窃听器 拍下了我的人
Wearing a wire, catching my boy on camera.
你应该在停户间里 躺在他旁边
You should be lying in the morgue right next to him.
你本来该去的
You would be, too,
但是你有守护天使
if it wasn't for your fucking guardian angels.
弗兰克
Frank.
杀死吉尔计划 第二阶段
Operation Kill Gill, phase two.
我们需要把艾萨克·特纳放在他最大的观众面前
We need to put Isaac Turner in front of his biggest audience yet.
在整个国家的见证下扳倒内政大臣
Take down the Home Secretary with the whole country watching.
这个蠢货每次公开否认
Every public denial this doofus makes,
故事就会变得更广为人知
the story grows bigger.
与此同时
Meanwhile,
艾萨克·特纳只想赶紧开始自己的新计划
Isaac Turner is simply trying to get on with his important new schedule -
-推广商业计划 开放战争纪念馆 -体育活动呢
- promoting business schemes, opening war memorials.  - Sports initiatives?
好
Yes.
但那些讨厌的记者一直缠着他
But those pesky reporters won't stop badgering him
问罗文·吉尔的事
about Rowan Gill.
为了公众利益 你同意接受独家采访
In the public interest, you agree to an exclusive interview.
听着 我不想表现得像是来复仇的
Look, I...I don't want, you know, to seem like I'm out for revenge.
我就知道你能懂
I knew you'd get it.
大概一个小时前
Approximately one hour ago,
我和内政大臣罗文·吉尔一起出席了一个简报会
I was present at a briefing with Home Secretary Rowan Gill,
我了解到他完全清楚「移花接木」
who I learned has full knowledge of Correction
及其在英国的使用情况
and its use within the UK.
哈特指挥官和总警司加兰德也在场
Also present was Commander Hart and DSU Garland.
最近好像有人想把你电脑上的信息都清除掉
It appears somebody recently tried to wipe it all from your computer.
就是藏在浴室里的那个笔记本电脑
The laptop hidden in your bathroom?
但是没有完全从回收站里删除
But hadn't quite managed to delete it from the deleted folder.
-典型的新手 -妈的 阿比盖尔
- Rookie mistake.  - Fucking Abigail.
我必须说 我觉得你的
I must say, I found it rather sweet...
小文章挺不错的
..your little journal.
不太像爱德华·斯诺登 更像是阿德里安·摩尔
Not quite Edward Snowden. More...Adrian Mole.
然后我提醒自己 天真和背叛
And then I reminded myself that naivety and treachery
并不是相互排斥的
are not mutually exclusive.
还有谁参与了
Who else is involved...
你的谋划
..in your plot?
-长官 -嗯
- Guv.  - Yeah.
我认为反恐司令部被刻意隐瞒了情报
I think the SO-15 contingent is seriously overdue a briefing.
昨晚我派了三个武装部队去搜查可疑车辆
I sent three armed units off to the suspect vehicle last night.
十分钟后 耳麦里报告说交火了 还说目标已倒下
Ten minutes later, we get "shots fired" over comms and "target down".
然后呢
And?
这三个小队 没有一个持械队员确认击毙
Between all three units, not one firearms officer claimed the kill.
你在质疑通讯被入侵了吗
You're questioning the comms traffic?
最近发生的事情 让我质疑一切
I'm questioning everything, after recent events.
-我没有没有拿下嫌疑人 -拿下了
- Did we take down a suspect?  - Yes.
-有尸体吗 -人被杀了一般都有尸体
- Is there a body?  - There usually is when someone's killed.
大家都说 当时一片混乱
There was a lot of confusion in the vicinity, by all accounts.
控制室里才一片混乱 长官
There was a lot of confusion in the control room, guv.
消失的车辆 耳熟吗
Disappearing vehicles - sound familiar?
这是先锋计划的重要一刻
A major event in Operation Vanguard
我们却什么都看不清楚
and not one of us had eyes on.
找个信得过的人
A bit of reassurance wouldn't go amiss
让我们安心一下也可以啊
from someone we can trust.
欢迎来到这场「移花接木」的噩梦 艾萨克
Welcome to the nightmare that is Correction, Isaac.
我们的敌人伪造了我们不能否认的事
Our enemies fake things which we can't deny.
这个视频文件上有很多信息
There's a lot of information on this video file,
我是说 并不只是罗文·吉尔
and I don't mean from Rowan Gill.
这种像素 说明使用的是媒体相机
The resolution suggests the type of camera used more by journalists
而不是警用相机
than police.
所以我再问你一遍
So I ask you again...
还有谁参与了
..who else is involved?
卡迪加·汗
Khadija Khan?
都结束了 瑞秋
It's over, Rachel.
从你第一次越界到最近一次的细节我们都有
We have everything from your first transgression to your most recent.
别忘了
Not forgetting...
这个小小的宝石
..this little gem.
帕特里克本来就不该是目标 对吧
Patrick wasn't meant to be a target, though, was he?
我们为你做了那么多 你就这样回报我们
After everything we've done for you, this is how you repay us.
-而且这也不是你第一次没能阻止了 -够了
- And it wouldn't be the first time you failed to stop it!  - That is enough!
汉娜·罗伯茨是英国的敌人
Hannah Roberts was an enemy of the British state.
你以为呢
What did you expect?
你们监视了我的家
You monitor me in my home.
你说什么
I beg your pardon?
每个房间都有摄像头 日夜监视着我
Cameras in every room, watching me day and night.
当然 我既不能证实
Naturally, I can neither
-也不能否认任何此类行动 -在我的卧室里
- confirm or deny any such operation. - In my bedroom!
-如果你被监视了 -看着我躺在床上
- If you were under surveillance... - Watching me in bed!
-事实证明这是完全合理的 -我都不能睡觉
- ..it's turned out to be entirely justified.  - I can't sleep!
-你秘密录下了英国情报 -我需要保险
- You secretly recorded British intelligence.  - I needed insurance!
你太让人失望了 瑞秋
What a crushing disappointment you are, Rachel.
明明给了你这么多机会
After all the chances you've been given.
从我加入机构的那一刻起你就一直瞒着我
You kept me in the dark from the moment I joined the department,
把我下放到地图部
banishing me to Mapping...
-你们这一代人是怎么 -一直监视着我
- What is it about your generation... - ..keeping me under surveillance.
即时满足感一旦被拒绝就崩溃
..that causes you to melt at the denial of instant gratification?
你应该将功赎过才对 你应该去赢得我们的信任
You were serving a penance. You were supposed to be earning our trust.
我本来对你印象深刻
I was impressed with you.
你看穿了这都是弗兰克·纳皮尔干的
You saw this was all Frank Napier's doing.
在我看穿之前
Before me.
在我们所有人之前
Before any of us.
你都能让那人当你面把自己所犯下的罪责和盘托出
You even managed to get the man to blurt out his culpability right in front of you,
即使这意味着你差点被割喉
even if it did mean nearly getting your throat slit.
你相当不错 瑞秋
You're not bad, Rachel.
你完全有能力胜任这份工作
You've got the capacity for the work, all right.
而你却白白浪费
And you want to squander it all...
就为了当个吹哨人
..so you can be some whistle-blower?
然后呢
And then what?
东躲西藏 跑去俄罗斯苟延残喘
Go into hiding, take refuge in Russia for the rest of your life?
你本有大把机会
There were opportunities for you.
现在也会有
Still would be.
我曾经有一刻以为能相信你
I mean, if I felt for a second I could trust you.
什么意思
What does that mean?
丹尼·哈特已经递交了辞职信
Danny Hart's handed in his notice.
反恐司令部需要个新指挥官
SO-15 will need a new commander.
新任反恐司令部指挥官是
The new commander of SO-15...
我么
..me?
不是 想什么呢
No. What?
是我
Me.
但要是我坐上丹尼·哈特的位置
But if I were to step into Danny Hart's shoes,
就得找人接替我的职位
I'd need someone to step into mine.
经过这些之后 你还指望我相信
You expect me to believe, after all this,
你会让我加入你的团队
you'd want me on your team?
我早该明白你是理解不了的
I should have known you'd fail to understand.
请谅解
Well, forgive me,
我更喜欢不牵扯谋杀和贪腐的工作
but I like my work a little less tainted with murder and corruption.
也许你脑震荡了
Perhaps you're concussed.
你 弗兰克·纳皮尔 格雷戈里·诺克斯
You, Frank Napier, Gregory Knox -
看来你们早就沆瀣一气了吧
I'm guessing you're all in on this together.
格雷戈里·诺克斯
Gregory Knox
是人类社会的祸害
is a scourge on human society.
他是当今世界中权力 政治和科技
He's everything that's wrong with power, politics and technology
所衍生出的污点
in the world today.
那你为什么要保护他
Then why are you protecting him?
你之前跟我说「移花接木」会用于伸张正义
You told me that I would see Correction used as a force for good.
我看到的却是被用来帮助像纳皮尔和诺克斯这样的人
I've seen it used to help people like Napier and Knox.
当发现弗兰克与此事有关 我跟你一样震惊
I was as appalled as you to discover Frank was involved in this.
但行动目的和运作方式是有区别的
But there's a difference between the aims of an operation and the running of it.
不管是什么 都让你成了谋害
Whatever it is, it makes you complicit in the murders
五个无辜之人的同谋
of five innocent people...
我决不会批准杀害英国国民
I would never sanction the killing of a British national.
参与掩盖真相
..complicit in the cover-up...
两者是不同的
The two things are not the same!
去跟法官解释区别吧
Explain the difference to a judge.
你真想知道吗
You really want to know?
我对这场风暴的介入
My intervention into this shitstorm
阻止了对英国人的杀戮 尤其是
prevented British killings - specifically...
对你的
..yours.
别跳
Don't do it!
你还好吗
Everything all right?
你看起来可不像是要迎接新的黎明
You don't seem on the precipice of a new dawn.
拿过来了吗
You have it?
你还指望是个大箱子么
Were you expecting a big suitcase?
被锁定了 需要密码
It's locked. Needs a code.
你任务完成后就能拿到了
And you shall have it upon completion of your work.
脑浆洒一地 这还不叫完成任务么
Brains on your flooring is not complete enough for you?
一点都不好笑 弗兰克 我都做噩梦了
That isn't funny, Frank. I've had nightmares.
我以为你会把她处理掉
I thought you were coming to deal with her,
而不是在我的走廊里解决你的内部争端
not settle your internal affairs in my corridor.
他们在处理了
They're cleaning it up!
记者在大楼附近打探消息
I've got journos sniffing around the building,
想挖黑料
and not the kind I like.
伦敦又有谣言说会有武装袭击
Rumours of another armed attack in London.
这个故事得收尾了
The story needs wrapping up.
不得有误
No loose threads.
这个
Well...
再说一遍 我不指望你能理解
Again, I wouldn't expect you to understand.
要是你能信任我
Consider this the sort of thing you might learn from me
而不是一直想着背叛我
if you could bear to give me your trust,
你可以从我身上学学这点
instead of constantly trying to betray me.
当警察发现阴谋 他们会实施逮捕
When the police uncover a conspiracy, they make arrests.
而间谍
A spy...
会扭转乾坤
..flips it.
引导其发展成对他们有利的局势
Keeps it running to their advantage.
不到36小时前 我确认了弗兰克·纳皮尔
I confirmed Frank Napier's involvement in this
与此事有关
not 36 hours ago...
当时他是去跟我分享情报的
..when he came to me in a sharing mood.
他的枪手就在你公寓外面待命
His gunmen were outside your flat,
等待他下令
waiting for his order.
你的摄像头拍到了他的人
You caught one of them on camera,
当然会成为弗兰克·纳皮尔的下一个击杀目标
of course you were going to be next on Frank Napier's kill list.
而你阻止了他
Until you stopped him.
我说服了他
Until I persuaded him
让我接手负责
to let me take the reins.
你怎么
How did...?
就当是我调解了一场道德领导力危机吧
Let's just say I mediated a crisis of moral leadership.
所以
So...
虽然你否定了我在行动中的作用
..I'm sorry if you disapprove of my joining the operation.
但要是我没参与
But if I hadn't...
机会的大门不会一直敞开 瑞秋
The door to this opportunity will not stay open long, Rachel.
我建议在它关闭之前 你要好好利用
I suggest you take advantage before it shuts.
把你收集到的所有「移花接木」的证据都给我
Give me everything you have on Correction,
告诉我你在跟谁合作
tell me who you're working with...
我们再想办法如何继续
..and we'll find a way to move on.
要是我不答应呢
And if I don't?
我的天
Oh, dear, oh, dear.
我就知道你会这么问
I thought you might ask that.
菲利普斯
Phillips.
如果我是你 我会做好心理准备
I'd brace yourself for this, if I were you.
每日新闻
■
实时：
内政部陷入混乱
仍在寻找告密者
西蒙·特纳在门口
Simone Turner is at Security.
什么事 艾萨克不在
Why? Isaac's not here.
她找的是你
She's asking for you.
知道了
OK.
我很好奇 你如果见识到「移花接木」的真正能力
I wonder if you'd be quite so determined to fight Correction
还会不会这么坚定地抵制它
if you saw what it was capable of.
我 瑞秋·凯里
I, Rachel Carey,
目前处于俄罗斯联邦法律管辖范围内
am currently within the legal jurisdiction of the Russian Federation.
俄罗斯政府已为我提供了安全避难
I have been offered safe harbour by the Russian state
我已经接受了
and I have accepted.
把那句改成"安全避难和庇护"
Make that "safe harbour and protection".
俄罗斯政府为我提供了安全避难和庇护
I have been offered safe harbour and protection by the Russian state
我已经接受了
and I have accepted.
"感激地接受"
"Gratefully accepted"?
我觉得挺好
Sounds good to me.
我很感激地接受了
And I have gratefully accepted.
当初发生在艾萨克·特纳身上的事 就是用的这个程序
This is the program used on Isaac Turner.
我忘了说参加行动的另一个好处
I forgot to mention the other perk of joining the operation.
魔法箱尽在我掌握
I have control of the kit.
对于自己的背叛 你会觉得内疚吗 凯里总督察
Do you feel guilty for your betrayal, DCI Carey?
会
I do.
我对自己的所作所为深感后悔
I deeply, deeply regret what I've done.
你赢不了的 瑞秋
You can't win, Rachel.
你肯定能看出来吧
Surely you can see that.
你看到内政部关于吹哨人的声明了吗 特纳先生
Have you read the Home Office whistle-blower's claims, Mr Turner?
拉尔夫 今天的焦点是这群年轻人
You know, Ralph, today's meant to be about these young people
在努力实现他们的目标
trying to achieve their goals.
好了 媒体朋友们
OK, fine people of the press,
请各位移步 前去接待室
if you'd care to decamp to the hospitality suite,
特纳先生将马上过去
Mr Turner will join presently
回答你们的所有相关问题
to answer any related questions you have.
请提问与本次活动相关的问题
Let's keep them related, please.
好了
All righty.
嗨 亲爱的
Hi, darling.
你没事吧
Are you OK?
你怎么
What are you...?
等下 你怎么知道我来这儿了
Wait. How...How did you even know I'd be here?
你早上发的推特都在说这事
You've been tweeting about it all morning.
什么事
What's up?
我去见了爱丽莎
I went to see Aliza.
爱丽莎 见她干嘛
Aliza? Why did you do that?
我以为能有所收获
I thought I might get somewhere.
收获什么
Somewhere with...?
没人愿意回答的问题
The question no-one seems inclined to answer.
没事吧
We good?
等一下
Erm, just a second.
如果维多利亚·贝洛在撒谎
If Victoria Bello was lying,
那她的申请为什么会被内政部阻挠
why was her application obstructed by the Home Office?
其实 我一直在调查这件事
Oh, right. You know, I've actually been looking into that.
我还去质询了内政大臣
I managed to collar the Home Secretary about it.
别编了 艾萨克 爱丽莎显然比我更了解你
You can stop, Isaac. Aliza obviously knows you better than I do.
整个议会都是
It seems the whole of Westminster does.
-西蒙 -为什么大家都觉得这是真事
- Simmy... - Why did they assume it was true?
可能是因为他们觉得
Erm...probably because they judge me
我和其他人一样 道德标准低的可怜
by the same pathetically low standards as the rest of them.
英国议会
The Palace of Westminster
基本上就是个中年危机援助中心
is basically a midlife crisis support centre.
-"我当时不在家” -继续
- "I was away from home."  - Go on.
"我当时不在家 那阵子也比较情绪化 她"
You know, "I was away from home. It was an emotional time. She's..."
她是个漂亮女生
She's a good-looking girl.
是吧 女人
Yes, I suppose. Woman.
你当时在跟我置气
You were in a mood with me.
我跟你
I was in a mood...?
那可是我母亲的葬礼
It was my mother's funeral.
没错 我很难过 我需要支持
Yes, I was upset. I-I needed support.
维多利亚·贝洛能满足你需求
And Victoria Bello gave you some.
不是
No.
以孩子们名义发誓
Swear on the children.
发... 什么
Swe...? What?
我得摆脱这种挥之不去的疑虑 艾萨克
I need to shake this lingering doubt, Isaac.
我要去开新闻发布会了
You know, I am in the middle of a press conference.
以孩子们的名义发誓 这一切都不是真的
Swear on the children none of it's true.
行吧
OK. OK.
我发誓
Erm...I swear. I swear...
以孩子们的名义 以我们 以及我所珍视的一切的名义
..on the children, on us, on everything I hold dear...
维多利亚·贝洛所说的都是假的
..Victoria Bello's claim was false.
她儿子不是我的
Her son's not mine.
很明显
Obviously.
你 没提交过样本吧
You...didn't submit a sample, did you?
做亲子鉴定
For the paternity test?
这问题不难答 艾萨克
It's a simple question, Isaac.
你提交过DNA样本吗
Did you submit a sample of your DNA?
没
No.
所以电视上的结果是伪造的 正如你说的那样
So, they faked the result on TV, like you said they would?
不是 结果是不匹配
No. The result was negative.
如果是伪造的 那应该是匹配
A fake result would have been positive.
也就是说 结果不如你意的时候才算伪造的
So...it's only fake if you disagree with it?
我不是那孩子的父亲 西蒙 大家都知道
I'm not the father of that kid, Simone. Everyone knows that.
-那是因为新闻上是这么播的 -对
- Everyone knows it because it's on the news.  - Yes.
你跟我说别相信新闻
You told me not to trust the news.
你们俩没事吧
How are we doing, guys?
你可以相信新闻 西蒙
Ok. You...You can trust the news, Simone.
你之前为什么说我不能信
Why would you say I couldn't?
我 我当时糊涂了
I...I was confused.
糊涂
Confused?
还要再等会儿吗
Need another minute?
那关于种族定性的言论呢
What about those racial profiling comments?
好吧
OK...
-怎么了 -你那会儿也是糊涂了吗
- What about them? - Were you confused then?
是
Erm...yes.
是发表言论的时候糊涂了
Confused when you made them,
还是你告诉我那些话不是你说的时候糊涂了
or confused when you told me you didn't make them?
天啊 艾萨克 你分得清吗
Jesus, Isaac! Do you even know?
完全是一团乱麻 西蒙
The confusion is pretty non-fucking-stop, Simone.
但现在 都回归正轨了
But now...now...things are good.
事态正朝看对我们有利的方向发展 所以你没必要一直问
Things are going our way. So you don't need to keep asking questions
把所有事都掰开揉碎了分析
and picking everything apart.
有必要 艾萨克 因为我要了解真相
Oh, but I do, Isaac, because I need to get to the truth.
我现在完全被蒙在鼓里
And right now, I'm nowhere fucking near it!
我怎么知道你跟她之间什么都没有
How do I know nothing happened between you and that woman?
因为我刚刚用孩子发誓了
Because you just heard me swear it on our kids' lives!
但你在顾左右而言他 对吗
But that's...that's not quite what you said, though, is it?
你觉得我听不出区别
You thought I wouldn't notice.
真不知道你在说什么
Oh, my. You have lost me.
你以为我傻吗
Do you think I'm stupid?
我太熟悉你们这些政客了
No.  I've been around politicians too long.
-行吧 我说什么了 -你说维多利亚·贝洛指控不实
- OK, what did I say, then?  - You said Victoria Bello's claim was untrue.
对
Yes.
-她儿子不是你的种 -他不是
- And that her son's not yours. Which he isn't.
但你没说你们之间什么都没发生
But you didn't say nothing happened.
如果没做亲子鉴定 艾萨克
How do you know her son's not yours, Isaac?
你又怎么知道她儿子不是你的
If there's no paternity test.
是因为你没睡她 还是因为你戴套了
Is it because you didn't fuck her or because you used protection?
艾萨克
Erm...Isaac.
-先他妈等着 -没事了
- Just fucking wait!  - No, it's OK.
我是来问真相的 我已经问到了
I came for the truth, I think I've seen it.
-听着 -你知道吗
- Listen...  - You know...
戴套也不意味看百分之百安全
You know condoms aren't 100%.
你知道的吧
Do you realise that?
艾萨克·特纳和我 都曾想着曝光「移花接木」
Isaac Turner and I discovered a shared interest in exposing Correction,
不过这位议员现在已经改了主意
an interest the MP no longer appears to share.
卡迪加·汗在演播室被黑之后
Khadija Khan became aware of Correction
意识到了「移花接木」的存在
after the hack on the studio.
你帮她意识到的
Because you enlightened her.
我认为她可以跟我一起当吹哨人 没错
I saw an ally in blowing the whistle, yes.
汗有拿到你这份录像吗
Does Khan have your dossier?
没有 长官
No, sir.
我担心她在证据不足之前操之过急
I was concerned she'd broadcast before I gained enough evidence.
所以决定不给她
I decided not to share it.
她知道「移花接木」的事
She knows about Correction.
-毕竟 -怎么
- I mean...  - What?
卡迪加·汗似乎只关心她自己
All Khadija Khan seems to care about is Khadija Khan,
她脑子里只有独家新闻
getting her claws into the next exclusive.
她明明知道采访维多利亚·贝洛
She knew that interview with Victoria Bello
会失去艾萨克的信任
would mean losing Isaac's trust.
但她控制不住自己
She couldn't help herself.
艾萨克·特纳不信任汗
Isaac Turner doesn't trust Khan?
还有一件事 长官
Erm...there's something else, ma'am.
我车里收音机下面藏了几张存储卡
You'll find copies of all the files in my dossier on SD cards hidden
里面是我所有的录像副本
beneath the radio in my car.
-吉玛 -安东尼
- Jen.  - Anthony.
我想请你帮个忙
I'm calling for a favour.
行啊 你了解我的
Right. Well, you know me.
听说你要退休了
You're retiring, I hear.
是想多陪陪家人
Spend more time with the family,
还是受够了负罪感的煎熬
or can't take any more guilt?
我们需要你提供一份口供
We need you to provide a statement.
关于录像吗
About the dossier.
关于先锋行动
About Vanguard.
作为昨晚事件的唯一目击者
As sole witness to last night's events,
你的证词至关重要
your testimony is critical.
你当时去特鲁罗的办公楼里例行调查
You were following up on a routine inquiry in the offices of Truro Analytics
这时候发现袭击者闯入大楼
when you became aware of intruders in the building.
当时的首要任务就是确保他们的假定目标
Your priority then became the safety of their assumed target -
格雷戈里·诺克斯的安全
Mr Gregory Knox.
在确保诺克斯安全后
Shortly after securing Mr Knox in his office,
武装支援及时赶到 消除了威胁
armed support arrived to neutralise the threat.
但因为他们执行的是一项秘密行动
Due to their ongoing deployment on covert operations,
武装人员的身份将从你的报告中删去
the identities of the armed officers will be redacted from your report.
但你可以指认被击毙人员的身份
However, you can confirm the identity of the man fatally wounded at the scene...
是尼古拉·米尔斯基
..as that of Nikolai Mirsky...
俄罗斯人
..a Russian national
也是涉嫌谋杀爱迪生·姚 约瑟夫·姆旺吉
and the prime suspect in the murders of Edison Yao and Joseph Mwangi,
杰森·麦肯纳 李·布拉德伯里
Jason McKenna, Lee Bradbury...
和帕特里克·弗林的头号嫌疑人
..and Patrick Flynn.
你居然没直接伪造我签名
Surprised you didn't just fake the signature.
你不担心莫斯科那边的反应吗
You're not concerned about the fallout from Moscow?
莫斯科方面会否认
Moscow will deny it,
但不会反驳
but they won't disprove it.
我宁愿如此
I prefer it that way...
真真假假 让大家不知道该信什么
..no-one knowing what to believe.
长官 我明白 你是要我配合做一场假戏
Sir, I understand that you are asking me to comply with a false-flag op
以保护弗兰克·纳皮尔和格雷戈里·诺克斯
to protect Frank Napier and Gregory Knox. I just...
我只想知道为什么
I'd just like to know why.
你听到那个混蛋的话了吗
You hear that prick?
把硬盘给我时 还让我等后续的密码
Hands me the drive, tells me I've got to wait for the code.
真有他的
Yes, I can believe it.
把里面东西弄出来
Get me into this.
诺克斯才是那个混蛋
Knox is the prick.
怎么哪儿都有你
You're kind of hard to get rid of, aren't you?
就像一坨硬屎 怎么也冲不掉
Like a stubborn turd - just won't flush.
不如你给瑞秋讲讲硬盘里的内容吧
Why don't you brief Rachel on the contents of that drive?
你在命令我吗
Is that an order?
是
Yeah.
格雷戈里·诺克斯或许是个真小人 但...
Greg Knox may be a piece of shit, but...
他手里有所有的科技大厂的数据
he crunches data for every big tech company that matters.
我们努力了很久
Know how long we've been trying
才跟这样的人达成交易
to make a deal with somebody like that?
什么样的交易
What kind of deal?
我帮他成为操纵政客的提线大师
I helped him play puppet master to his politician.
作为回报 他给我提供秘密武器
For that, he gave me the secret weapon -
特鲁罗的算法
Truro's algorithm.
全球近30亿社交媒体账户权限
Access to almost 3 billion social media accounts worldwide.
所以你们能追踪到任何人活动
So you can track the activity of just about anyone?
不是追踪 是预测
Not track - predict.
这个算法能预测出一个人的行为趋势
The algorithm calculates behaviour right down to how suggestible a guy
不管他是想换牙膏 还是想投票给谁
is to changing his toothpaste or who he's going to vote for.
也可以预测出他有多反叛
You can also predict how prone he is to dissent.
从曼谷到墨西哥城 再到俄勒冈州的波特兰
Anyone from Bangkok to Mexico City to Portland, Oregon
任何人动一下颠覆的心思 我们都知道
even thinks about subversion, we'll know about it.
但要是进不去硬盘 这一切都白搭
Not if we can't access the drive, we won't.
那我看的是什么
What am I looking at?
我们只能访问 但无法迁移和修改
Well, you're looking at it - I just can't transfer it.
你能黑进BBC 却黑不进去这个
You mean you can get into the BBC but you can't hack into this?
他们用了AES256加密算法
This has AES 256-bit cipher.
我要是黑进去 数据会丢失
I can hack it, if you want to lose data.
诺克斯为什么不给你密码
Why won't Knox give you the code?
他不满意我们的工作
He's not happy with the work...
死的那些人
..carnage...
尸体的线索
..the trail of bodies.
他担心会怀疑到自己身上 对吗
He's concerned it might all lead back to him, right?
对
Right.
他会给我密码的
He'll give me the code -
等大家的注意力转移到别处去的时候
when everybody is looking the other way.
转移到东边
East.
你做得很好 瑞秋
Good work, Rachel.
这对全球安全有着里程碑式的重要意义
A landmark move for global security.
民主就靠边站了
If not democracy.
你这么快就忘了吗
Have you forgotten already?
我是怎么教你让形势为我们所用的
What did I teach you about flipping an operation to our advantage?
你守好这里 托德
The room's yours, Todd.
瑞秋和我要出去一下
Rachel and I are stepping out for a while.
我们要去哪里 长官
Where are we going, ma'am?
弗兰克刚才说
You heard Frank.
格雷戈里·诺克斯想嫁祸于一个听命于科技大厂的政客
Gregory Knox is trying to plant a politician who answers to big tech.
我们得去阻止他
We are going to stop him.
能给我一杯淡伯爵茶吗 多加奶
Can I get a very weak Earl Grey with lots of milk?
你的全方位人工智能还好吗 格雷戈里
How's the all-seeing AI, Gregory?
那个强有力的项目
The great and powerful programme.
出什么问题了吗
Is there a problem?
嗯 是有点小问题
Erm...a slight problem, yes.
我遇到了个小麻烦
It seems I've hit a slight bump in the road
看来你的算法没能预测到
that your algorithm failed to predict.
-西蒙说她要离开我 -这么快
- Simone says she's going to fucking leave me.  - Already?
什么
Al...? What?
哦 好吧
Ah, right.
你似乎一点都不紧张
You...You don't seem too alarmed.
如果我真的离婚了 你的算法对我竞选成功的几率
I can't imagine your algorithm's going to love my chances of success
应该不会很乐观吧
if I end up getting divorced.
这个可说不准
You can never second guess that thing.
怎么 如果我真的被甩了 反而不会有问题吗
So what? We might not have a problem if someone does, in fact, leave me?
不一定
Not necessarily.
你已经知道了
You knew?  Hmm?
你早知道
You knew. You knew.
你早就知道维多利亚· 贝洛的事
You knew dragging Victoria Bello out the woodwork
会摧毁我的婚姻
would destroy my marriage.
不 我知道有这个可能
No, I knew it...it might.
什么鬼
It...? What the fuck?
艾萨克 我们初次见面时你就说自己想出人头地
Isaac, you told us when we first met you wanted to get to the top.
但不代表我想妻离子散
Not if it meant losing my family.
-你没明确说明 -你疯了吧
- You didn't stipulate that. - Are you insane?
真抱歉 艾萨克
I'm sorry, Isaac,
但程序不喜欢你和西蒙在一起
but the program just doesn't see you with Simone.
很大一部分选民认为
A significant percentage of the electorate perceives
你的婚姻太讨巧了 他们不喜欢
your marriage as somewhat strategic and they don't like it.
你觉得这是我第一次听到这种话吗
Do you really think it's the first time I've heard that -
我娶西蒙是为了往上爬
that I married Simone to climb the ladder?
这种话我都听了13年了
I've had it thrown at me for 13 years.
你要是真觉得我会向这种话低头
So if you really think I'm going to give in to it now,
就让你和你的算法都去死吧
you and your algorithm can both go fuck yourselves.
-一派胡言 -这是大家的想法
- It's bullshit.  - It's what people think.
你为什么不去改变大家的想法
Then why don't you change what they think?
-这不是你的职责吗 -我的职责是让你当选
- I thought that was your job. - My job is to get you into power.
你的职责是走上巅峰 改变世界
Your job is to change the world when you get there.
先生们
Ah, gentlemen.
猜猜我刚才跟哪个电视台的混蛋通话来着
Guess which swinging dick of broadcasting I've just got off the phone to.
■
OBE电视
即原创黑人娱乐电视，是2003
年9月推出的英国电视频道。该
频道面向非洲观众，播放来自南
非、尼日利亚和加纳的节目。
安东尼·里德 OBE的
Anthony Reed OBE.
他想做独家专访 周四晚8点 BBC一频道
He's offering an exclusive interview - Thursday night, 8pm, BBC One.
咱们排个期吧
Shall we pencil it?
那个男孩呢
What about the boy?
男孩
The boy?
阿曼迪
Amandi.
维多利亚的儿子
Victoria's son?
既然你知道这么多 那就给我个准信儿吧
Seeing as you seem to know so much, I thought you might oblige me.
什么准信儿
What about?
他是
Is he...?
你儿子吗
Yours?
天啊 真想不到
Heavens, I have no idea.
竟然有些细节 连我都不知道 艾萨克
There are some details, Isaac, even I'm not privy to.
-淡伯爵茶 多加奶 -完美
- Weak Earl Grey with lots of milk.  - Ah, perfect.
嗯 我们
Erm, are we...?
去见卡迪加·汗
Meeting Khadija Khan.
你要是想说动卡迪加
If you're hoping to flip Khadija, ma'am,
或许不该带我去
I'm the wrong person to take with you.
-我们之前闹翻了 -我知道
- We didn't end on good terms. - I know.
先锋行动失败的时候
I deployed someone to keep track of your movements
我派人监视过你的一举一动
while Vanguard was down.
我猜这对你来说一定很尴尬吧
I imagine this is going to be pretty awkward for you, huh?
我最近遇到了麻烦
I find myself with a problem.
有些高度涉密的情报泄露到了你这里
Some highly classified intelligence has recently been disclosed to you.
既然总督察凯里都来了 你应该明白
I trust DCI Carey's presence leaves you in no doubt
我指的是什么情报
as to what intelligence I am referring.
凯里总督察会同意
As DCI Carey will confirm,
发生严重泄密事件的同时
this serious breach
也恰逢她警探生涯的低谷
coincided with a period of personal difficulty for the detective,
她现在意识到 自己当时的心理和精神状态不佳
which she now recognises impacted negatively on her mental health and wellbeing,
某些行为也非常得不专业
in particular her behaviour in the workplace.
如果我说错了 你可以随时纠正
Forgive me if I'm speaking out of turn.
没有 你说的很对
No. I can confirm all of that.
怪不得你那天在楼下冲我大喊大叫
It explains the public outburst.
上一个这么吼我的人 已经去《第一秀》剪片子了
Last person who yelled at me like that's now editing the One Show.
我理解 想赢得你的合作
So, I realise I need something solid on the table
我得提供些实实在在的东西
if I'm to earn your cooperation.
我们部门很久以来都与你们台的一个信得过的人
The service has long enjoyed a mutually beneficial relationship
保持着长期互惠互利的关系
with one trusted individual inside this organisation.
而这个人已经不再年轻了
The incumbent isn't getting any younger.
安东尼·里德
Anthony Reed?
他是内鬼
He's a fucking spook?
你在某些方面比他更懂行
In some ways, you're better informed than him already,
我敢说短期之内 我们就能达成一个行动目标
and I'll wager we can agree on one operational goal in the immediate term.
你是想收买我吗
Sorry, are you tapping me up?
没有正式合同 也无财务协议
There's no official contract, no financial agreement.
你的回报就是为国家安全尽一份力
Your reward will be doing your bit for national security
以及英国情报部门的丰富信息来源
and in the bountiful source of information that will become available to you
将向你全面开放
from the all-seeing eye of British intelligence -
直接且独家
directly and exclusively...
向你开放
..to you.
行动目标是什么
What operational goal?
我将崛起
今天 一场高度复杂的针对持枪袭击的案子 画上了句号
Today brings to an end a highly sophisticated campaign of targeted gun violence
它已困扰反恐指挥部
that has gripped counter-terrorism command
长达6天之久
for six long days.
BBC新闻
杀害帕特里克·弗林探长的凶手被击毙
这次毁灭性的袭击夺走了
A devastating campaign that has claimed the lives
五条无辜的生命
of five innocent victims -
探长 帕特里克·弗林
警官 李·布拉德伯里
警官 杰森·麦肯纳
其中三名是在职警察
three of which were serving police officers.
这场搜捕行动在对峙中
The manhunt was concluded in a standoff
以一名39岁白人男子被持枪警察打中要害而宣告结束
during which a 39-year-old white male was fatally wounded by firearms officers.
此人的身份已被确认为尼古拉·米尔斯基
The identity of the individual has been confirmed as Nikolai Mirsky,
是俄国人 也是我们调查的头号嫌疑人
a Russian national and the prime suspect in our investigation.
■
诺克斯
解锁密码
120389060891
尽情享用
虽然我们还在评估他们的袭击动机
Our assessment of the motive for these attacks continues,
但压倒性的证据表明
but the evidence overwhelmingly indicates
此事有外国特工的参与
the involvement of agents of a foreign state.
在此 我要向那些
I would like to pay a heartfelt tribute to those officers who made
为了保护我们
the ultimate sacrifice...
而牺牲生命的警官们
..giving up their lives...
致以诚挚的敬意
..in the service of protecting us.
我说过你该给她打个电话
I did say you should give her a call.
是的 长官 你说过
You did, ma'am, yes.
是瑞秋吗
It's Rachel, isn't it?
伊冯 对你的遭遇我深表遗憾
Yvonne, I'm so, so sorry for your loss.
他们说事发时你也在场
They told me you were there when it happened.
我...
I...
袭击当晚我是第一个到达现场的人
I was the first to reach the ward the night of the attack,
但我到的时候 帕特里克他
but, by the time I got to Patrick...
我不是说帕特里克 我是说那个俄罗斯人
I'm not talking about Patrick. I'm talking about the Russian.
他死的时候你在场
You were there when they killed him.
是的
Yes.
谢谢
Thank you.
凯里 你得来皇冠酒吧
You're coming down the Crown, Carey.
整晚的酒我们都包了
You're not putting your hand in your pocket all night.
不用了
I don't think so.
你是先锋队的英雄 你不去我们也不去
You're the hero of Vanguard. We're not going without you.
也许你应该去
Perhaps you ought to...
英雄
..hero.
-阿比 -我认真考虑过要不要看新闻
- Abi.  - I was seriously thinking about checking the news
看你是否被人抛户荒郊野外
to see if you'd been found in a ditch somewhere.
抱歉 是我不好
Sorry. Shit sister.
那天一切都顺利吧
Was that all right the other day?
笔记本电脑的事情
The laptop?
我做对了吗
Did I do it right?
对 阿比
Yeah, Abi.
你做得很好
You did it just right.
我要挂电话了
I've got to go.
明天会很忙
Big day tomorrow.
他该何去何从
Should he stay or should he go?
就在吉尔为自己的政治生涯而战的时候
As Gill fights for his political life,
看到内政部危机的安全大臣可能会发出决定性一击
the security minister who saw the Home Office crisis from inside could deliver the decisive blow.
请观看今晚BBC一频道的现场直播
Join me for an exclusive interview with Isaac Turner,
对艾萨克·特纳的独家专访
tonight live on BBC One.
新闻之夜访谈
晚上8点
BBC一频道
看内政部
Home Office.
风云变幻
Home truths.
好 第一手资料
Right. So, first-hand knowledge,
吉尔阻挠了维多利亚·贝洛的申请
Gill obstructed Victoria Bello's application.
但却为他管家的签证
Fast-tracked his housekeeper's visa, his wife's
他妻子表亲的护照申请开通快速通道
cousin's passport application.
我知道 这个已经说过了
Yes, I know. We've been over this.
格雷戈里想让我们再梳理一遍
Well, Gregory would like us to run over it again.
里德人呢
Where's Reed?
见鬼
Oh, shit.
抱歉耽搁了 马上就到 安东尼
"Apologies for the hold up, nanoseconds away, Anthony."
特纳先生 您准备好了我们就开始
We're ready to line up when you are, Mr Turner.
-您的水 特纳先生 -谢谢
- Here's your water, Mr Turner. - Thank you.
给您别一下麦
Just going to mic you up.
6分钟后切画面
Intercept in six minutes.
摄像转播正常 镜头正在拍摄
Camera feed secure. Video capture in progress.
开始
Bring it up.
我还记得我第一次的时候
I still remember my first time.
我检查一下麦克风的音量
Can I just check the level on that mic?
您今早吃的什么
What did you have for breakfast?
-鸡蛋 吐司 咖啡 鱼子酱 -没问题
- eggs, toast. Coffee? Caviar.   - Perfect.
里德在哪
Where...Where is Reed?
艾萨克 我来了 临危受命
Zac, catch me. I'm parachuting in.
-你不是安东尼·里德 -谢谢
- You're...You're not Anthony Reed. - Well, thanks.
你也不是首相 我们随遇而安吧
You're not the Prime Minister, but we play the hands we're dealt.
安东尼深表歉意 家里有事
Anthony sends his apologies. Family matter.
但我不这么想
I have my theories.
-胡闹 我不拍了 -什么 为什么
- Bollocks. I'm pulling it. - What? Why?
走吧
Let's go.
我需要请示领导
I should really call the office.
不必了 我不拍了
You don't need to call the office, I'm pulling it.
这次访谈已经做过预告了
The interview's been trailed, mate.
没错 但不是让她来提问
Yeah, not with her asking the questions, it hasn't.
艾萨克
Isaac.
艾萨克 你真的要单方面决定不拍吗
Isaac. You really want to make this decision - unilaterally?
里斯 告诉我 你为谁工作
Rhys, remind me - who do you work for?
这个问题不刁钻 也不难回答
No, it's not a trick question or a difficult one.
你为我工作 但如果你想另谋高就
You work for me, but if you'd rather work for someone else, please,
随你便 滚吧
by all means, fuck off!
艾萨克
Isaac.
清场 梅尔 把这个撤了
Clear set. Strike this please, Mel.
谢谢 还有水
Thank you. Take water.
把麦给她别上
Let's get her mic'd up.
4分钟后开播
Intercept in four minutes.
谢谢
Thank you.
进来 放这里
Come right in. Right over here.
数字作图中
Digital asset rendering.
比利 你有镜子吗
Billy? Do you have a mirror, please?
检查一下电池 没问题吧
Check the batteries on that. Yeah? Good?
里德在哪
Where...Where is Reed?
-早餐吃的什么 -喝了点粥
- What did you have for breakfast? - I had some porridge.
-胡闹 -够了吗
- Bollocks.  - Got enough?
够了 数字形象准备就绪
More than enough. Digital assets standing by.
喂
Hello.
听着 我取消了访谈
So, listen, I've pulled the interview.
什么
What?
20秒后传送信号
20 seconds to transmission.
启用数字形象
Deploy the asset.
数字形象已就绪
Asset deployed. Asset deployed.
BBC一频道现在播放内政风云
Time for some home truths now on BBC One.
本节目最新更正
In an update to our advertised programme...
安东尼·里德没来
Anthony Reed never showed.
最后卡迪加·汗出现了 我觉得不对劲
Khadija Khan turned up at the last minute. Something's not quite right.
对万众瞩目的议员的独家现场采访
..an exclusive live interview with the MP on everybody's mind.
你取消了采访吗
You've pulled the interview?
对 我走了
Yes. I walked.
真相即将揭晓
The truth is coming.
相信我 一旦真相大白 你们就明白了
And when it comes, you'll know about it, believe me.
无需证明
If proof were ever needed
在政界 一周是相当长的时间
that a week is a long time in politics,
在艾萨克·特纳身上重演 仅7天
hit replay on Zac Turner's. In just seven days...
60秒后开播
60 seconds to intercept. 60 seconds to...  Digital asset
数字形象准备就绪
standing by. Digital asset standing by.
-堪比肥皂剧的内政部丑闻 -我们不用
- ..a Home Office scandal worthy of soap opera.  - We don't have to...
-不 没关系 -最新转折是
- No, no, it's fine. - The latest twist has seen Zac
艾萨克通过内政部吹哨人的帮助
strike back with the help of a Home Office whistle-blower
以及前上司罗文·吉尔的丑闻档案 华美转身
and a dossier of dirt on his former boss, Rowan Gill.
去死吧你们
Motherfuck you all!
今晚 来自伦敦的独家现场专访 我们将听到
Tonight, in an exclusive interview live from London, we hear from
-艾萨克·特纳 -30秒后开播
- Isaac Turner...  - 30 seconds to intercept.
-画面正常 -讲述他职业生涯中最受争议的一周
- Eyeline check.  - ..about the most controversial week of his career,
-他的政治野心 -卡迪加
- his own political ambitions... - Khadija.
以及他认为该由谁
..and who he believes should take the hit...
-怎么样 -画面正常
- How's that?  - Eyeline set.
-清场 清场 -为内政部的危机负责
- Clear frame. Clear frame.  - ..for the crisis at the Home Office.
她没问题吧
Is she going to be all right?
希望你知道自己在干什么
I hope you know what you're doing.
我正在去你那的路上 听着
I'm heading back to you right now. But, listen,
咱们需要谈谈
the two of us need to talk.
开播倒计时 6 5 4
Intercept in six, five, four...
事情必须有所改变 懂吗
Things have got to be different, OK?
从现在起 我要参与每一个决定
From now on, I want to be involved in every decision.
知道吗
OK?
-格雷戈里 -你走了
- Gregory?  - You walked.
对
Yes.
直播开始 直播开始
Intercept is live. Intercept is live.
内政部本周是否解雇了不该解雇的人
Was the wrong man fired from the Home Office this week?
如果你指的是我的前同事内政大臣
If you're referring to my erstwhile colleague, the Home Secretary,
这不是我的决定 我不是首相
it's not my call to make. I'm not the Prime Minister.
如果议会那边的传言属实
If the rumours in Westminster are to be believed,
-你是想成为首相的 -议会的传言有待澄清
- you'd like to be.  - Oh-ho, in Westminster's a big if.
但也不否认吧
It's not a denial, then?
卡迪加 我觉得 经历过这一周后
After the week I've had, Khadija, I think it'd be unwise for me
-竞选首相是不明智的 -格雷戈里 喂
- to launch a bid for Number 10. - Gregory? Hello?
-就为了内政部 -你是谁
- Just the Home Office? - Who is this?
格雷戈里
Gregory, it's...
是我啊
..it's me.
你说过不再作假的
You said no more deep fakes.
英国需要一个负责任的内政部
Britain deserves a Home Office that's fit for purpose.
我试过阻止他们了
I tried to stop them.
-真的 -是真的他吗
- I really tried.  - Is it fucking him?
你在说什么
Is what fucking him?
英国需要一位德能配位的内政大臣
Britain deserves a Home Secretary who's up to the job.
-我不知道怎么回事 -好
- Ah... I don't know what this is.  - Right.
胜任这份工作 不是说让特警部队东走西逛
By up to the job, I don't mean scurrying around SW1A getting caught up
被指控行为不端
in allegations of misconduct.
他做得挺好
He's doing OK.
■
威斯敏斯特
英国议会大厦所在地
-而是走出威斯敏斯特的泡沫 -格雷戈里
- I mean rising above the Westminster... bubble   - Gregory?
直面英国民主面临的每一个威胁
to confront every threat to British democracy head-on.
但是格雷戈里 那不是他
But, Greg...Gregory. It's not him.
师傅 麻烦掉个头
Erm, excuse me. Can you turn around?
我要回酒店
I need to go back to the hotel.
你好 打扰一下
Hello. Excuse me.
师傅 听得见吗
Driver! Hello!
你是在暗示英国民主面临的威胁
Are you suggesting there are threats to British democracy
-没有得到正视吗 -不是暗示 卡迪加
- not being confronted?  - I'm not suggesting it, Khadija,
我说得非常清楚
I'm saying it loud and clear.
能说明一下这些威胁的本质吗
Can you indicate the nature of some of those threats?
一个词
Two words...
科技大厂
..big tech.
-什么 -科技大厂
- What?!  - Big tech?
不管格雷戈里·诺克斯给你多少钱 都不值得
Whatever Gregory Knox is paying you, it's not going to be worth the hell
如果不掉头 我就要发火了
I'm going to unleash if you don't turn this fucking car around!
众所周知科技和社交媒体在极大程度上
We all know the extent to which technology and social media
渗透进了我们的日常生活中
has infiltrated our daily lives.
我们的家里 电脑屏幕上
It's in our homes, it's on our screens.
让我们的孩子沉迷成瘾
It's got our children hooked.
我敢说 这个国家我不是唯一一个
I dare say I'm not the only dad in the country who regrets giving in
向女儿智能手机让步的父亲
to their daughter's demands for a smartphone.
细节不错
Nice detail.
而且还渗透进了我们的政治体系
But it's also infiltrated our political systems -
■
特纳痛斥
科技巨头
-不光是英国 全球皆如此 -如何渗透
- not just in Britain, but around the world.  - Infiltrated how?
未经我们同意就获取我们的数据
By harvesting our data without our consent
并利用它干涉选举 公投 政治竞选
and using it to interfere with elections, referendums, political campaigns.
你是说科技公司
You're saying that tech corporations
直接干涉了英国政治
are meddling in UK politics directly?
不是直接
Well, not directly.
见不得人的的工作往往由硅谷以外的
The dirty work tends to be done by data analytics companies
-数据分析公司完成 -该死的
- outside of Silicon Valley.  - Shit!
比如说在英国吗
Here in the UK, for instance?
没错 我就知道英国有这么一个公司
I can think of one such example here in the UK, yes.
弗兰克 是你吗
Frank, is this you?
你他妈要对我做什么
What the fuck are you doing to me?!
情节有多严重 是非法的吗
How much of this is illegal?
只需想想 这些家伙在逃税避税方面
Well, we've seen how nimble these guys can be
是多么无所不用其极
when it comes to dancing around tax laws.
显而易见 卡迪加 如果英国的民主
Clearly, Khadija, if a plot to affect British democracy
被外国人的阴谋左右
was directed by a member of a foreign state,
这就是严重的国际事件
that's a serious international incident.
如果这些阴谋还得到了英国人的帮助
If a British national is found to have colluded in such
那这些人就是叛国
an attempt, that's treason.
我的天
Holy shit!
他已经开始逃了
Is he fleeing already?
我猜他要逃到厄瓜多尔
My money's on Ecuador.
-你觉得我们能拿他们问责吗 -目前不行
- Do you see any hope of holding them to account?  - Not as things stand.
这些科技巨头一副难以撼动的姿态
Tech giants behave as if they're untouchable.
英国需要一位内政大臣 确切来说 是一位首相
Britain needs a Home Secretary - indeed, a Prime Minister -
告诉他们 我们不怕
who isn't afraid to tell them otherwise.
什么叫全没有了 怎么可能
What do you mean, none? How's that possible?
在收到活检结果之前
We knew it was going to be inconclusive until we received
一切还有变数
the results of the biopsy.
所以从干疮百孔变成完全没有
So, from riddled to all clear?
我知道这挺罕见
I agree it's unusual.
CT成像会有误检的概率
Erm, CT imaging throws up anomalies from time to time,
但很少会差这么多
but rarely this inconsistent.
-你需要回来做个活检 -等一下
- You'll have to come in for a biopsy.  - Wait a second.
你给我看的那些图像
These images you've been showing me -
器官上布满阴影的那些图像
black tar covering all my internal organs -
都是电子版的吧
did you receive those electronically?
-全都是电子版的 -用邮件发送吗
- It's all electronic.  - By email?
都在医院的服务器上 我就是从那儿下载的
Uploaded to the hospital servers. I get it from there.
他妈的
Motherfucker.
令人担忧的是 科技行业对于干预选举的问题
Alarmingly, the tech industry has done absolutely nothing
一直作壁上观
to combat the issue of election interference.
我不禁要问问为什么
And, frankly, one has to ask why.
事实上 我们需要想一想 企业能从中捞到什么好处
In fact, one has to wonder what such corporations have to gain.
我没理解错的话 凯里总督察 你似乎挺享受这感觉
If I'm not mistaken, DCI Carey, you appear to be enjoying this.
格雷戈里·诺克斯的计划失败
Gregory Knox's plan has been sabotaged.
一场针对英国民主的袭击得以避免
An attack on British democracy has been averted.
尤其要感谢你的工作
Thanks to your work in particular,
为弗林警长的家人伸张了正义
DS Flynn's family feel a strong sense of justice for Patrick.
你现在也看到了 这个「移花接木」的程序
Are you starting to see the potential for good in this strange
它有用的一面了吧
little programme we call Correction?
弗兰克
Frank!
你还好吗
Are you OK?
好极了
Never better.
壮得像头驴
Fit as a mule, apparently.
医生说我可能得的是良性胃溃疡 不过
I mean, doctor says I may be looking at a benign stomach ulcer, but...
你是说
You mean...?
活检报告出来了
Biopsy report came back.
我没得癌症
I don't have cancer.
真是难以置信
But that's...incredible.
可不是吗
It is incredible,
就在前几天 我的CT扫描
when you consider that, just the other day, my CT scan
-还说我浑身是瘤呢 -说不通啊
- indicated I was riddled with it. - It doesn't make sense.
就在我告诉你我的病情后
That's right after I told you how sick I was.
-你得再去做些检查 -你他妈的干了什么
- You need to go in for some more tests.  - What the fuck did you do?
-我干了什么 -别他妈骗我
- What did  I  do? - Don't fucking lie to me.
弗兰克 你这是在说啥呢
Frank, I have no idea what you're talking...
-我知道你是幕后主使 -你貌似很生气
- I know you're behind this. - You're obviously very upset.
跟我说什么救赎 什么主日学校
All that talk about redemption, about Sunday School.
你想夺走我的行动 对吧
You wanted my fucking op, didn't you?
你搞了一出烂摊子
Well, something had to be done after the shit shower
-我总得做点什么吧 -你他妈疯了吗
- you made of it! - Are you out of your fucking mind?
还黑了我的医疗记录
You hacked my medical records!
爸妈吵架确实挺心烦的吧
Don't you hate it when mum and dad argue?
你现在不会死了 这不好吗
Think about it. You're not dying - it's good...
脚本编辑中
别担心 我帮你
Don't worry. I've got you.
这是好消息 弗兰克 你不会死了 多好啊
It's good news, Frank. You're not dying. It is good...
-好消息 -你知道我有多难过吗
- It's good news!  - Have you any idea what I've been through?
-我站在屋顶上 -你干啥了
- I was up on the roof.  - You were what?
我看着下面的车流
I was looking right down into the traffic.
我差点想跳下去
I could have jumped!
不过 卡迪加
But, obviously, Khadija,
政府还在其他方面辜负了我们
there are other ways in which the government has failed us.
-其他方面 -真跳下去就太遗憾了
- Which other ways?  - Well, that would have been deeply regrettable.
遗憾
Regrettable?!
-我会摔在人行道上 摔成番茄蛋汤 -等等
- I would have been tomato bisque on the sidewalk.  - Wait!
-你他妈疯了吗 -等等
- Are you fucking nuts?  - Wait!
目前已知 深伪技术已经在
is the extent to which deepfake technology has already
-我们社会蔓延开来 -你什么意思
- pervaded our society.  - In what sense?
英国当局使用深伪技术
The truth is, deepfakes have been deployed by the British
-已经很多年了 -这是什么
- authorities for a number of years now...  - What's this?
用来威胁我们民主 自由的核心价值观
..in ways that threaten our core values of democracy, liberty...
-这是什么 -包括立法
- What is this?  - ..rule of law.
特纳先生 你得承认英国当局
Mr Turner, you have to admit that the idea of British authorities...
这不在脚本里 不是我写的脚本
This is not in the script.  This is not my script.
有人破坏行动
This operation is compromised.
破坏 你他妈在说什么
Compromised? What the fuck you talking about?
-这是你给我的脚本 -不 这不是
- It's the transcript you gave me.  - No, it isn't.
卡迪加 别再说了
Khadija, wrap it up.
你换了脚本吗
Did you switch the script?
-当然没有 -卡迪加 停下
- No, of course not!  - Khadija, wrap it up.
-快停下 -深伪技术被用于
- Wrap it up.  - Deepfakes are deployed...
-停下 卡迪加 -她听不到你说话
- Khadija, wrap it up! - She can't hear you.
除非她也参与其中了
Unless she's in on it.
全都掐掉
Shut the whole thing down.
-我进不去 -数字形象还是信号
- I can't get in!  - The asset or the transmission?
全部
Everything.
全部掐掉
长官 你不能切断直播
Ma'am, you can't cut the broadcast.
现在他只是个散播阴谋论的政客
Right now, he's just a politician with a conspiracy theory.
但如果掐断了 所有人都会相信的
Shut it down, everyone will believe it.
她说得有道理
She's got a point.
哦 是吗
Does she?
特纳先生 深伪技术都用在哪些方面
Mr Turner, deepfakes have been deployed in what way?
他们称之为「移花接木」
They call it Correction.
这是一种通过干扰摄像头信号
It's a method of real-time video manipulation,
利用深伪技术实时操控视频的方法
using the disruption of camera feeds and the deployment of deepfake technology.
你说的"他们"指的是谁
Who do you mean by "they"?
我们自己的情报机构
Members of our own intelligence services,
我们的政府和警察
our government and the police.
但特纳先生 我想问清楚 你在断言
But, Mr Turner, to be clear, you're asserting that there's some
我们英国情报部门有一个制造假视频的项目
sort of programme within British intelligence to create fake video footage.
举个例子 他们获得了恐怖阴谋的情报
Well, let's say they have intel of a terrorist plot,
但针对嫌疑人的证据不足
but the evidence against the suspects is insufficient...
他们会伪造犯罪视频
They make up incriminating footage?
用他们的说法 是把情报转化为证据
Well, THEY would say they turn intelligence into evidence.
-瑞秋·凯里 -这个指控非同小可
- Rachel Carey... - This is a serious accusation.
你因违反《官员保密法》而被捕
..you are under arrest for breach of the Official Secrets Act.
你可以保持沉默 但如果在某些问题上知情不答
You do not have to say anything, but it may harm your defence
会在审判中对你不利
if you do not mention when questioned...
抱歉 长官
I am sorry, ma'am,
但你现在处于美利坚合众国的法律管辖之下
but you're currently within the legal jurisdiction of the United States of America.
弗兰克
Frank.
只要你还在他国法律管辖范围内
Whilst you remain within the legal jurisdiction...  You don't have
就不能在美国管辖范围内抓人
the power to arrest.  ..of the United States of America,
你必须遵守美国的法律
you must abide by the rules, regulations
-和法规 -弗兰克
- and limitations of US... - Frank!
-你能闭嘴吗 -如果不介意的话
- Would you shut the fuck up? - Now, if you'll excuse me,
我先出去了
I know how this ends.
弗兰克 拜托拘留凯里总督察
Frank, please detain DCI Carey.
我有理由怀疑她参与了颠覆活动
I've reason to suspect she's involved in subversive action against the state.
又没颠覆我的国家
Not my state.
她没提到一丁点美国
He hasn't said anything about the US.
弗兰克 帮帮忙
Frank, help!
我的天啊
For crying out loud!
她给我安排了癌症 又来找我帮忙
She gives me cancer, then she asks for my help.
踏出这栋楼一步
The moment you set foot outside this building,
我就有资格逮捕你
you are eligible for arrest!
我们不都一样吗
As we all are...
长官
..ma'am.
瑞秋
Rachel!
听我说
Listen!
你根本不知道自己做了什么
You don't know what you've done.
我只知道一件事
I know one thing...
帕特里克·弗林讨厌「移花接木」
..Patrick Flynn hated Correction.
-这个所谓的「移花接木」-「移花接木」项目
- And this so-called Correction...   - Correction programme.
「移花接木」项目 你什么时候知道的
Correction programme - when were you made aware of it?
-在我也深受其害时 -深受其害
- When I became a victim.  - A victim?
大家可能已经注意到 我最近说了
People may have noticed there have been a number of things
一系列不符合我性格的话
I've said out of character recently -
一些我绝对不主张的荒谬观点 比如种族定性
absurd ideas I would never advocate. Racial profiling, for example.
你是暗示 你那些话不是你说的吗
Are you suggesting that it wasn't you who made those comments?
我不是暗示 我这次要让大家都听到
No, I'm not suggesting it, Khadija, I'm saying it loud and clear.
特纳先生 你必须承认
Mr Turner, you have to admit that the idea of...
我一直觉得你这丫头能成事儿
I always knew you were destined for greatness...
-制造虚假证据 -不管以什么办法
- ..creating false evidence... - ..one way or another.
你前一秒还在否认的事
..you were railing against a moment ago.
你应该下去看看
You should get down there.
你错过了一场好戏
You're missing the best bit.
你不担心大家会把它当成
You're not worried people will think this is
脑洞大开的阴谋论吗
some outlandish conspiracy theory?
大家应该质疑
Well, people should question it.
我们需要质疑我们看到和听到的一切
We need to challenge everything we're told and question everything we see.
每次看到一段视频 或听到一段录音
We need to ask of every voice on every recording of every image
都应该问问自己
on every screen...
如何证明这是真的
..how do we know this is real?
例如 在他的采访中
In his interview, for example.
-虽然宣称是现场直播 -这就是现场直播
- It purports to be a live broadcast. - Well, it is a live broadcast.
你能证明吗
Can you prove it?
我可以在网上看到最新的头条
Well, I can go online, show the latest news headlines.
好吧 我们看到了一些东西 那我呢
All right, now we're getting somewhere. But what about me?
你怎么了
What about you?
我看起来是艾萨克·特纳 听起来也是艾萨克·特纳
Well, I look like Isaac Turner, I sound like Isaac Turner.
但如何确定我就是真人
How do we know I'm the real deal?
谁又知道真正的艾萨克·特纳现在是不是
Who's to say the real Isaac Turner isn't in a car, right now,
正坐车在去皮卡迪利广场的路上
on the way to Piccadilly Circus?
谁能保证这次采访的摄像头没有被黑
Who's to say the cameras filming this interview haven't been hacked?
谁又能保证 艾萨克·特纳的形象
Who's to say Isaac Turner's image
没有被人工智能截获操控
hasn't been captured, animated by artificial intelligence?
谁又知道 从采访的一开始
Who's to say, since the very start of this interview,
你以为你面前的是艾萨克·特纳
while you believed you were watching Isaac Turner,
实际上你看到的是我
you were, in fact, watching me -
一个深伪出品的赝品
a deepfake. Fake...
一切真假难辨
It's impossible to say.
当然 如果你现在正好在皮卡迪利广场
Unless, of course, you happen to be in Piccadilly Circus right now
亲眼看到了艾萨克·特纳
and can see Isaac Turner with your own eyes, then...
才叫眼见为实
..perhaps you can.
如果你在皮卡迪利广场或附近
If you are in or near Piccadilly Circus,
请环顾四周
look around you.
拿出手机 开始拍摄吧
Take out your phones and start filming.
希望携起手来 我们能够照亮
Hopefully, together, we can shine a light on the challenges
这个充斥着深伪挑战的世界
we face surrounding deepfakes.
希望我们大家提高对非法「移花接木」技术的意识
And, hopefully, we can begin to raise awareness of the illegal practice of Correction.
因为只有把这个阴谋公之于众
Because only by bringing this conspiracy out into the open
才能正视这个问题
can we hope to confront it.
正如大家所见 跟我一起在演播室的不是特纳议员
As you can see, I'm not in the studio with Isaac Turner MP.
特纳先生现在正在皮卡迪利广场
Mr Turner is in Piccadilly Circus,
在这场让大家瞠目结舌的节目中
graciously playing his part in our, hopefully,
扮演着他的角色
eye-opening stunt.
大家看到的是一场深伪采访
You have indeed been watching a deepfake interview.
但刚才提到的让大家大开眼界的「移花接木」
But the alarming practice of Correction described in it
都是真的
is very much real.
在一群来自英国情报核心部门的吹哨人的帮助下
Working with a team of whistle-blowers from the heart of British intelligence,
BBC已经取得证据
the BBC has obtained evidence that knowledge
英国多个情报机构及政府高官
of the so-called Corruption programme extends across multiple UK
都参与了所谓的「移花接木」项目
intelligence agencies and to senior members of the British government.
今晚开始 我们会带来一系列独家报道
In a series of exclusive reports, starting tonight,
详细披露这些令人不安的细节
we will be examining these alarming revelations in detail.
我们会把BBC获得的证据分享给大家
We will be sharing the evidence obtained by the BBC.
那些幕后黑手终将对此事负责
And, finally, we will be confronting those ultimately responsible.